Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ huyennguyen410 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Business Analytics Azure studio Business Analysis

Huyen Nguyen (Karen)

Business Data Analyst

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary

I've been a Data Analyst for 6 years. I enjoy working on data with complex, time-sensitive tasks/projects while maintaining a high degree of accuracy and productivity.

Working in a service company brings me knowledge about fields such as Sales, Finance, Inventory, Banking, Procurement, Refinery. That great values help me so confident about my journey and promote me to try and try every day.

I want to improve myself, increase my knowledge of new fields, and advance in work in the future.

Experience

Innovature BPO
Business Data Analyst
January 2023 - Present (2 years 3 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Preparing data, build reports in Tableau/Power BI to demo/POC for Clients
- Analyzing data and document KPIs
- Building and maintaining reports/dashboard on Tableau/Power BI
- Testing value to ensure the accuracy of the numbers on the reports/ dashboards
- Building internal dashboards for management

Pinnacle Group, Inc.
Business Data Analyst
January 2023 - Present (2 years 3 months)

MyMind - MSM Đồng hành Chuyển đổi số Senior Data Analyst November 2022 - December 2022 (2 months) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Supporting DMS team to build stored procedure in SQL and report template in Stimulsoft.

- Building User Performance dashboard for client to evaluate the effective users and consider how many accounts have not been used to inactive licenses

Freelancer

Data Analyst

May 2019 - November 2022 (3 years 7 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Freelance Tableau/PowerBI

Getting requirements, analyze data, and build dashboard/reports in Tableau/ PowerBI in fields such as Sales, Finance, Education, Hospital, Digital marketing

Datatyk

Data Analyst

May 2019 - May 2022 (3 years 1 month)

District 3, Ho Chi Minh City

DATATYK is a service company.

We use Power BI to build BI Reports for Customer.

My responsibility is:

- Preparing data, build reports in Power BI to demo/POC for Customer
- Working face-to-face with Customers to get requirements
- Analyzing data and document KPIs for Data Engineer
- Building reports on Power BI desktop
- Testing report to ensure the accuracy of the numbers on the report
- Training users to use Power BI for self-service analysis on Power BI Service

I joined 6 projects and supported 2 others to get requirements.

The projects include Sales FMCG, Finance, Medical,...

BSD INSIGHT

Data Analyst

April 2017 - April 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Binh Chanh District, Ho Chi Minh City

BSD is a service company.

We use Tableau to build BI Dashboard for Customer.

My responsibility is:

- Preparing data, build reports in Tableau to demo/POC for Customer
- Working face-to-face with Customers to get requirements
- Analyzing data and document KPIs

- Building datamart and reports on Tableau desktop
- Testing report to ensure the accuracy of the numbers on the report
- Training users to use Tableau Desktop for self-service analysis

I joined 2 projects and supported 2 others. In addition, I participated in 4 Tableau training projects for clients, 3 of which I was the main trainer. The projects include: Sales, Banking, and Inventory

Education

University Of Economics Ho Chi Minh City Bachelor's degree, Business Statistics · (2013 - 2017)